Guide to the George H. Brown papers, 1757-1933 and undated, bulk 1850-1878
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
George H. Brown papers 1757-1933 and undated, bulk 1850-1878
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Brown, George Hubbard, 1850-1926.
3.0 linear feet Extent: Circa 817 items
Lawyer, superior court judge, associate justice of North Carolina Supreme Court, active in Washington (Beaufort Co.), N.C. Professional correspondence, indentures, deeds, wills, receipts, a memorandum book, and other papers, mainly dating from 1850-1878 and largely relating to George Hubbard Brown, an attorney from Washington, N.C., and his legal practice, and to his service as associate justice of the North Carolina Supreme Court. There is a small amount of correspondence, among which are letters from John Humphrey Small, U.S. Representative from North Carolina.
RL.00175
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The George H. Brown papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1948.
Collection Overview
Indentures, deeds, wills, receipts, a memorandum book, and other papers, mainly dating from 1850-1878 and largely relating to George Hubbard Brown, an attorney from Washington, N.C., and his legal practice, and to his service as associate justice of the North Carolina Supreme Court. There is a small amount of correspondence, among which are letters from John Humphrey Small, U.S. Representative from North Carolina.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Brown, George Hubbard, 1850-1926; Small, John H. (John Humphrey), 1858-1946; Lawyers -- North Carolina -- Correspondence; Judges -- North Carolina -- Correspondence; North Carolina -- Officials and employees; North Carolina -- Beaufort County -- History; Washington (N.C.)--History; Photographs
Related Material
In memoriam, George Hubbard Brown, late associate justice of the Supreme Court of North Carolina [memorial pamphlet with portrait, 1926]
Rubenstein Library and University Archives, Duke University
Contents of Collection
- George H. Brown papers, 1757-1933 and undated, bulk 1850-1878, (4 boxes)
  - Letters, 1873-1878, Washington, D.C., (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1879-1933, Washington, D.C., (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Letters, undated, Washington, D.C., (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Bank book and memorandum book, (2 volumes) (Box 1)
  - Bills and receipts, 1757-1830s, (1 folder) (Box 2)
  - Bills and receipts, 1840s-1850s, (1 folder) (Box 2)
  - Bills and receipts, 1860s, (1 folder) (Box 2)
  - Bills and receipts, 1870s, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Bills and receipts, 1880-1933, (1 folder) (Box 4)
  - Bills and receipts, undated, (1 folder) (Box 4)
  - Photographs, (11 items) (Box 4)